bookmarkinsider.com 2013-06-09

# Privacy Policy | Vertical Insider

Vertical Insider is owned and operated by Vertical Insider LLC. Vertical Insider LLC, its subsidiaries and affiliates (collectively “Vertical Insider LLC”) respect your privacy. Our purpose in collecting information from you is to help us provide you with better service, such as notifications about special offers and promotions. We will not willfully disclose any individually identifiable information about you to any third party without first receiving your permission, as explained in this privacy statement.

**Key Definitions**

In this Privacy Policy, we use the following key definitions. Other terms are defined in the body of the policy.  
“Click stream Data” means the information that Vertical Insider LLC collects through cookies, log files, beacons and clear GIFs, as described in Section 4 below.  
“Content Provider” means a third party that owns a white paper, analyst report or other document and allows Vertical Insider LLC to link to or display that document on the Sites.  
“User” or “you” means any person viewing any page of the Sites.  
“Third Party Content” means the white papers, analyst reports and other documents available through the Sites and owned by Content Providers.

**What Information Do We Collect?**

Profile Information: Our primary goal in collecting profile information (which may include your name and the following business – and not home or personal – information: title, address, phone number, fax number and e-mail address) is to provide you with the best and most useful content and services, and to offer you opportunities to obtain other products and services from us and our partners. Because we derive revenue mainly from advertising, collecting information is essential to keeping our services affordable to users.

We collect profile information when you provide it to us through the following: when you register on one of our sites, or an e-mail newsletter, register for one of our events or register to use certain services (like webcasts and white papers). Several of the services that we offer on our sites may require registration as a condition of use. Once you register with one of the Vertical Insider LLC network of sites, including VerticalInsider.com, BookmarkInsider.com, you are no longer anonymous to us. We may also receive information about you from other sources, such as Dunn and Bradstreet, and add it to the information you provided to us.

Cookies: Like most sites, for account management purposes, Vertical Insider LLC uses cookies. Cookies are data files stored on your computer that identify you as a unique user. Cookies enable us to track user trends, preferences and patterns to better understand our user base and to improve the quality of our service. Most browsers permit users to refuse cookies or to be notified before a cookie is accepted. You can visit our site without using cookies.

Subscriber Information: If you subscribe to an email newsletter and become a “Subscriber”, Vertical Insider LLC collects your email address, password and areas of interest. Member Information: If you register as a Member (such as by registering on a content directory, subscribing to a newsletter, registering on VerticalInsider.com, BookmarkInsider.com and/or our other aforementioned web properties, Vertical Insider LLC collects additional information, including your name and corporate title, the name of your company and the department in which you work, your industry group, country, zip code and telephone number (“Member Details”). At the time you register to become a Member, or later when you access a particular page or document, Vertical Insider LLC may collect additional information, including but not limited to: information about software or hardware your company is using, plans your company may have to purchase additional products/services, etc.. All of this information together is included in the definition of “Member Details”.

Sharing Information: We aggregate profile information and disclose such information in a non-personally identifiable manner to advertisers and other third parties for marketing, promotional, and other purposes. Except for the specific instances of information-sharing described above, we do not disclose to third parties any information that could be used to identify you personally.

**How Do We Use The Information We Collect?**

Profile Information: Vertical Insider LLC collects profile information supplied by visitors who register, as described above. That information lets us better tailor our content to visitor interests and helps our advertisers better understand the audience they are reaching. Most of Vertical Insider LLC is free and is supported by paid content and sponsorships from our advertisers.

Cookies: Vertical Insider LLC uses persistent cookies to link Members to their registration information, which allows our system to confirm a user’s identity and access level on the Sites. Vertical Insider LLC also uses that information to track service selections, and save passwords so that Members do not have to log in each time they visit the Sites.

**Usage of Cookies for Ad serving**  
Other cookies without personally identifying information and data are used to enable Vertical Insider LLC to manage the online advertisements presented or personalized information to the user. Browsers or third-party software can allow you to block the use of cookies while you surf our site. Or, you can use third-party “anonymizer” services to mask information in your cookies, or even general data such as your IP address. In such cases you would not be able to take advantage of most of the personalization services offered by Vertical Insider LLC.

Vertical Insider LLC serves all advertising on Vertical Insider LLC network affiliated web sites, email newsletters, RSS feeds, and other online mediums. When Vertical Insider LLC is serving ads, it recognizes certain types of non-personally identifiable information, such as a user’s IP address, browser version or type, operating system, service provider and time zone. We also use cookies to note the general content of the sites that users visit over time in order to serve ads on this site and other sites.

Clear GIFs & Servers: We use these tracking technologies for a variety of purposes, including:

  * Keeping count of return visits to our site or our partners’ sites
  * Accumulating and reporting anonymous, aggregate, statistical information on Web site and content usage to our partners and customers
  * Determining which features visitors like best to help us improve our content and site, personalize your user experience, and measure overall site effectiveness

Subscriber Information: We use Subscriber Information to deliver email newsletters on topics of interest to Subscribers who have signed up for those services. We may also send general promotional and marketing materials to Subscribers. We use Subscriber Information and Supplementary Information in aggregated form to understand our customer base and to market our services to our customers.

Sharing Information: Vertical Insider LLC may share profile information collected:

  * When we have your consent to share the information.
  * When you register or log in to access vendor content or when you register to attend a vendor-sponsored event (including Webinars, Conferences, Custom Media events and Editorial events). The vendor’s use of that information is governed by the vendor’s privacy policy and may be used for follow up by telephone, email, direct mail or other common methods. You should contact these vendors directly if you have any questions about their use of this information.
  * Profile information collected when you register or log in on a co-branded partner site is generally available both to Vertical Insider LLC and that partner. However, the partner’s use of that profile information is governed by the partner’s privacy policy and may be used for follow up by telephone, email or other common methods. You should contact these partners directly if you have any questions about their use of this information.
  * Vertical Insider LLC does not share any of your profile information with any person or entity, unless you register to access vendor content, register to attend a vendor-sponsored Vertical Insider LLC event (including Conferences, Custom Media events and Editorial events), register for our Newsletters.

**Information Collection and Usage of Data of Registered Users**  
When you register with the Vertical Insider LLC Network, we ask you to share limited information about yourself and the company you represent. We only disclose business information that you are authorized to disclose. During interactive sessions, we may also collect your opinions and preferences regarding certain information technology products or services. We use this information to provide you with quality services as well as with offers that we think are relevant to you based on the preferences you share at registration or during interactive sessions.

Using your contact information, Vertical Insider LLC may also send you e-mail messages under the following circumstances, among others:

  * To respond to an inquiry or request for information
  * To thank you for contacting Vertical Insider LLC or any of its wholly owned subsidiary web sites
  * To welcome you to Vertical Insider LLC or any of its wholly owned subsidiary web sites and to its products and services
  * To explain new product offerings and features of our services
  * To notify you of special promotions
  * To communicate with you regarding customer service related issues.

**Users Outside the US**

While we make every effort to honor the laws and wishes of all users, this Web Site is available for users located exclusively in the United States of America and therefore may not recognize foreign laws.

**Registration**

In order to use many features of the Web Site and to participate in interactive sessions, you will be asked to complete a registration form. During registration, you are required to provide contact information, for you and the company you represent as well as business information about the company you represent. Vertical Insider LLC may use this contact information as a means of confirmation of your identity, position, or relationship to particular enterprise of company.

**Information Collection and Use From Registered Users**

When you register on Vertical Insider LLC or any Directory, we ask you to share limited information about yourself and the company you represent. Only disclose business information that you are authorized to disclose. During interactive sessions, we may also collect your opinions and preferences regarding certain information technology products or services. We use this information to provide you with quality services as well as with offers that we think are relevant to you based on the preferences you share at registration or during interactive sessions.

Please see the Information Sharing and Disclosure section below. Using your contact information, Vertical Insider LLC may also send you e-mail messages under the following circumstances, among others:

  * To respond to an inquiry or request for information
  * To thank you for contacting Find White Papers
  * To welcome you to Find White Papers and to its products and services
  * To explain new product offerings and features of our services
  * To notify you of special promotions
  * To communicate with you regarding customer service related issues.

Your contact information may be made available or provided to third-party service providers and contractors (such as the Website webmaster) that are contractually obligated to protect your information as disclosed in this Privacy Policy. In order to maintain accurate records concerning communications that Vertical Insider LLC may have received from or sent to you, Vertical Insider LLC may also indefinitely store any information that you provide to Vertical Insider LLC through the Website.

**What Information Do We Disclose to Third Parties?**

Disclosure of Anonymous, Aggregated Information We provide summary reports to our Content Providers, based on our analysis of Click stream Data. The type of information included in a summary report is “3,000 people looked at your information this week, and of those people 60% clicked through to read the full report.” This aggregated information is anonymous and does not disclose to the Content Providers any Member Details about the individual users who saw or clicked on their reports.

Vertical Insider LLC also discloses aggregated user statistics (for example, 25% of our users are interested in Networking) in order to describe our services to prospective customers and partners, and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes.

Disclosure of Personal Information  
Philosophy: The Content Providers make the Third Party Content available through Vertical Insider LLC in return for receiving the contact information of Users who view their Third Party Content. Accordingly, if you view Third Party Content, Vertical Insider LLC may disclose your Member Details, Click stream Data and Supplementary Information to the Content Provider, as set forth in more detail below. If you do not want this information disclosed to a Content Provider, do not view the Third Party Content. Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy, Vertical Insider LLC will not disclose personal information to any third parties. Notwithstanding the foregoing, Vertical Insider LLC may at any time disclose profile information to third parties if we are required to do so by law, regulation or court order.

Member Information: When you view Third Party Content, Vertical Insider LLC may disclose your Member Details and Click stream Data, together with Supplementary Information, to the Content Provider. Vertical Insider LLC’s customer agreement with the Content Provider: (a) provides that the Content Provider may use this information only to send you product information, to contact you via common methods of communication to assess your interest in its products and services, and to assess your interest in the Content Provider’s products and services; and (b) prohibits disclosure of this information to any third party other than agents of the Content Provider for the permitted marketing purposes set forth above. You should contact the Content Provider directly if you have any questions about their use of this information.

**Log Files**

We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the Web Site, track user’s movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses that we collect are not linked to personally identifiable information.

**Notification of Policy Changes**

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you about significant changes to our Privacy Policy by placing a prominent notice on our Web Site or sending an email to the address you provided to us. Vertical Insider LLC welcomes comments and questions on this policy.

**Security Precautions**

Vertical Insider LLC takes precautions to protect data and information under its control from misuse, loss or alteration. Vertical Insider LLC’s security measures include industry-standard technology and equipment to help protect your information, and Vertical Insider LLC maintains security measures to allow only the appropriate personnel and contractors access to your information. Unfortunately, no system can ensure complete security, and Vertical Insider LLC disclaims any liability resulting from use of the Website.

If you have any questions about the security at our Web Sites, please [contact us](http://itknowledgehub.com/contact/).

**Exceptions**

Other than as set forth above, Vertical Insider LLC will not otherwise use or disclose any of your personal information except to the extent reasonably necessary to: (i) process your information and to correct technical problems and malfunctions in the Website or the computer systems supporting the Website; (ii) protect the security and integrity of the Website; (iii) protect the rights and property of  Vertical Insider LLC and others; (iv) take precautions against liability; (v) respond to claims that your information violates the rights and interests of third-parties; (vi) respond to judicial or administrative process or otherwise comply with applicable law; and (vii) to assist law enforcement agencies in connection with investigations or matters related to public safety.

**Updating Personal Information**

You may update or correct information you previously provided to Vertical Insider LLC by accessing your user profile on our various directory web sites.

**Links to Other Web Sites**

VerticalInsider.com and BookmarkInsider.com are two of the properties within the Vertical Insider LLC network of sites. Each of these sites hosts thousands of white papers as well as white paper Research Libraries on third party sites. Some Third Party Content made available through the Research Library sites is maintained on the website of the Content Provider, and not on the Vertical Insider LLC network of sites. This means that when you click through to that Third Party Content, you will be leaving the Research Library and the Vertical Insider LLC Network. It will be clear to you when this happens, as the look and feel of your web page will change, and the URL will no longer refer to a website in Vertical Insider LLC network of sites. This Privacy Policy does not govern the use and disclosure of any information you choose to disclose to the Content Provider on the Content Provider site.

In addition, the Sites you are viewing may be co-branded, meaning that the Sites are branded with the logos of both Vertical Insider LLC and a third party (“Co-Branded Sites”). If you register or log in on a Co-Branded Site, you are choosing to disclose information to both Vertical Insider LLC and the third party with whose brand the site is co-branded. This Privacy Policy only governs Vertical Insider LLC’s use of your information. The third party’s use of that personal information is governed by the partner’s privacy policy, and not by this Privacy Policy.

The Vertical Insider LLC Web Site also contains links to other Web Sites. Please be aware that Vertical Insider LLC is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to read the privacy statements of each and every Web Site that you visit from our Web Site or through the interactive sessions.

**Questions or Comments**

Regarding the Privacy Policy For additional questions, or to be taken off our marketing lists, please contact us.
